OLGA KURBATOVA

I'm a QA Engineer with experience in functional testing (manual). I'm testing web-apps, mobile apps, virtual voice assistants, API. I'm interested in business processes and test-automation (now studying Python for automation purposes), also I like to work with data.

CONTACT ME AT

- **(2)** +7 916 885 18 36
- kurbatova.olga.a@gmail.com
- in <u>@olga-kurbatova-qa</u>
- Moscow, remote, ready to relocate

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Jira (Zephyr, X-Ray), Confluence
- TestRail, TestIT
- Postman, Swagger
- Android Studio (device logs)
- Charles
- Hoverfly
- Rancher, ArgoCD
- GitLah
- Kibana, OpenShift (reading logs)
- Jenkins (basics)
- MS SQL/PostgreSQL
- Non-SQL DB (MongoDB)
- Python (basics)

LANGUAGES

- Russian (Native)
- English (B2)
- French (A1)
- Spanish (A1)

QA ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Engineer

MegaFon | Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

<u>Project:</u> selfcare services mobile app (iOS, Android) for mobile operator Ucell (Uzbekistan)

What I did:

- Requirements testing
- Estimation of tasks, sprint volume planning
- Developing of check-lists and test-cases
- Test data preparation (json files, user parameters, environments configuration)
- Bug reporting
- Frontend/backend testing
- Testing of integration with external systems using Hoverfly for mocks
- Using GitLab: making new branch for test environment, testing in it using mocks, merging into master branch
- Communication with the team on different topics: working process, tasks, instruments
- Functional, UI, smoke, regression, acceptance, exploratory testing, bug-fix retesting

QA Engineer

Deutsche Telekom IT Solutions | Nov 2021 - May 2022

<u>Project:</u> automation of the internal vacation accounting and financial reports system (web)

What I did:

- Test-design & test execution, regression testing
- Estimation, refactoring and maintaining of test documentation
- Test data preparation
- Ul testing
- Exploratory testing
- API testing (REST/Postman)
- Integration testing
- Communications with Product Owners, Developers, and Testers

OLGA KURBATOVA

EDUCATION

2007 - 2012 • National Research University Higher School of Economics Public Administration (Urban studies) Specialist

2012 - 2014 • National Research
University Higher School of Economics
Public Administration (Strategic
management)
Master

QA ENGINEER

Test Engineer

IBS Appline | Apr 2021 - Nov 2021

<u>Project:</u> e-commerce mobile app (iOS and Android) with virtual voice assistant

What I have done as the only tester in the project:

- Created test-model and maintained test-documentation
- Communicated with Product Owner, Developers, and Testers
- Tested new features and bug fixes
- Implemented regression testing
- Did UI and exploratory testing
- Tested API with Postman (REST)
- Tested mobile apps and virtual voice assistant

Senior Consultant

Publicly funded national institution "Small business of Moscow" | Feb 2013 - Apr 2021

Tax&Law counsulting